{"questions":[{"difficulty":1,"questionId":2,"question":" 2. What is the primary purpose of using prototypes in requirements engineering?","answer3":"To provide a visual representation for better understanding of requirements","answer2":"To replace the final software product","answer4":"To finalize the project schedule","correct_ans":"3","answer1":"To demonstrate the final software product to stakeholders"},{"difficulty":1,"questionId":8,"question":"8. Why is scalability an important consideration in software architecture?","answer3":"It focuses on the security aspects of the software","answer2":"It ensures that the software has a visually appealing design","answer4":"It addresses the system's ability to handle growth in users","correct_ans":"4","answer1":"It determines the project timeline"},{"difficulty":1,"questionId":10,"question":"10. What is the main distinction between validation testing and defect testing?","answer3":"The focus on system crashes in defect testing","answer2":"The intentional obscurity of test cases in defect testing","answer4":"The expectation of correct performance in validation testing","correct_ans":"4","answer1":"The use of artificial data in validation testing"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":3,"question":"3. Why is requirements traceability important in software development?","answer3":"It ensures that requirements are not changed","answer2":"It determines the project's return on investment","answer4":"t helps in creating user stories","correct_ans":"1","answer1":"It enables tracking of requirements throughout the development process"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":4,"question":"4. In Agile development, what is the primary responsibility of a Scrum Master?","answer3":"Ensuring the team follows Agile principles and practices","answer2":"Managing the project budget","answer4":"Creating user stories and acceptance criteria","correct_ans":"3","answer1":"Writing code and developing features"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":5,"question":"5. What is the purpose of a Burndown Chart in Agile development?","answer3":"To visualize the team's skill levels","answer2":"To track the team's progress in completing tasks over time","answer4":"To display the hierarchy of user stories","correct_ans":"2","answer1":"To measure the project's return on investment"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":7,"question":"7. what does software architecture include?","answer3":"The interactions between a system and its environment","answer2":"Only the behavioral aspects of a system","answer4":"The fundamental organization, components, and design principles of a system","correct_ans":"4","answer1":"Only the structural aspects of a system"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":9,"question":"9. What is the primary purpose of program testing?","answer3":"To discover defects before the program is put into use","answer2":"To identify as many requirements as possible","answer4":"To verify the software's non-functional attributes","correct_ans":"3","answer1":"To execute a program with real-world data"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":11,"question":"11. What is the primary focus of software maintenance?","answer3":"Creating different versions of custom software","answer2":"Developing new software from scratch","answer4":"Developing generic software products","correct_ans":"1","answer1":"Modifying a program after it has been put into use"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":12,"question":"12. In adaptive and perfective maintenance, what does the maintenance programmer need to be an expert in?","answer3":"testing and documentation","answer2":"New programming languages","answer4":"Requirements,Specifications,Design,and Implementation and integration","correct_ans":"4","answer1":"implementation and integration"},{"difficulty":2,"questionId":14,"question":"14. When designing a survey in software engineering, what is a crucial consideration?","answer3":"Excluding open-ended questions","answer2":"Focusing on positive feedback","answer4":"The length of the survey","correct_ans":"4","answer1":"Using complex technical language"},{"difficulty":3,"questionId":6,"question":"6. What is the purpose of using architectural patterns in software development?","answer3":"To provide reusable solutions to commonly occurring problems","answer2":"To estimate the return on investment","answer4":"To assign tasks to team members","correct_ans":"3","answer1":"To document the project budget"},{"difficulty":3,"questionId":13,"question":"13. What is the primary purpose of conductive surveys in software engineering?","answer3":"To promote new software releases","answer2":"To collect data on specific software-related topics","answer4":"To identify and fix bugs in the software","correct_ans":"2","answer1":"To gather user feedback on software performance"}]}